We're going to talk about testing and Python.
Tests are a cornerstone of a solid Python program.
And thankfully, because of Python's batteries
included philosophy, everything that we need to write unit tests
is included in the standard library.
So let's learn about the basics of unit testing.
Unit testing is a method of testing software methods
where individual functions are tested in an automatic fashion
to determine if they work as expected.
These automated tests, they help you find bugs quicker
and faster than not testing at all or even manual testing.
And you can also write them alongside or before you
write your functions in a style called test-driven development
to help your code be as bug free as possible.
There are three types of automated tests
that can be performed at different levels of abstraction.
Unit tests operate on the small testable unit of code,
usually a function that does a single action or an operation.
Integration tests will check to see
of different units or modules of code work together
as a group.
And then functional tests operate on units of functionality
to make sure that a specific function of the software is working.
And it may involve a lot of unit tests
or whole systems working together.
For this class, I'm just going to show you how to write unit tests,
but know that testing the real world
are pretty essential for your Python production programs.
They're very helpful because many companies
use a style of development called CICD
or continuous integration continuous deployment.
That means a lot of unit tests, integration tests,
maybe even a few functional tests, which run automatically
before your code is merged in with the deployed master branch.
If the test fail, the deployment can be stopped
or not happen at all.
The developers can be notified.
And your broken code doesn't make it
into your production servers.
But this technique only works if you write a lot of good tests.
It can be a bit complicated to set this up properly,
depending on which deployment strategy you're using,
but it really saves you an enormous amount of time in the long run
and helps your users to not see bugs.
So before we talk about unit tests and solves,
Python comes with something called the assert keyword.
And that kind of helps you do a little bit of quick sanity checking.
In assertion, just checks condition, the Boolean value
of a condition to see if it's true or false, if it matches.
If the assertion is true, the program will continue.
If it's false, you'll see an assertion error
and your program will stop.
So let's say, going back to my repal.
Let's say, I have a number A. I can type assert A
is greater than 0 when that pass is just fine.
If I assert that A is less than 0, I'm going to get an assertion error.
Know that assertion errors are for sanity checking,
they're not for production.
Simple checks, sanity checks.
They're not for validation.
Certainly not for validating any type of user input
or determining if a file isn't found something like that.
These situations are better suited for raising an actual exception.
And the other thing about assertions
is they're not guaranteed to be run in your production code.
It's easy to turn off, disable all assertions at runtime,
just by starting your Python program with a particular flag.
So never rely on assertions to run on production code.
Never use them for validation.
Never use them for user input validation.
Makes sense?